# Jerome Thayananthajothy

+44-7498-373069 · tjthavarshan@gmail.com · thavarshan.xyz 41 Fitz Roy Avenue, Harborne, Birmingham, B17 8RL

### SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Engineering professional and collaborator with 5+ years of experience devoted to Software Development, 2+ as a Team Lead. In-depth knowledge of SQL and NoSQL databases, PHP, TypeScript and related frameworks, AWS, Docker, licensing with external partners and approval standards. Proficient at multitasking and management of large 10+ or small 4 person teams with a proven track record for being highly efficient at developing budget sensitive product using group brainstorming, innovation, graphics, and materials that tell a story and resonates with consumers in varied account types and retail experiences.

### **SKILLS**

#### **Expert in**

PHP, TypeScript, JavaScript, Python, MySQL, PostgreSQL, Laravel, Symfony, VueJS, NodeJS

### Intermediate in

Machine Learning, C++, Java, MongoDB, ReactJS, NestJS, ExpressJS, Flask

### Basic in

Rust, DynamoDB

### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

## MacroActive Ltd · Colombo, Sri Lanka

Jun 2021 - Nov 2022

### **Senior Software Engineer**

- Worked extensively with PHP, TypeScript, VueJS, ReactJS AWS Dynamo DB and MongoDB.
- · Designed, developed and deployed three major projects and was working on fourth project before
- Responsibilities included but was not limited to training new recruits, performing code reviews and planning weekly sprints.

## Elegant Media · Colombo, Sri Lanka

Apr 2019 - Jul 2020

### **Software Engineer**

- Designed, developed and deployed numerous Laravel projects.
- Performed code reviews and was one of the biggest contributors to the internal projects and systems of the company.

### Seven's Idea · Colombo, Sri Lanka

Jan 2018 - Mar 2019

### **Software Engineer**

- Designed, developed and deployed numerous WordPress and Laravel projects including the main IT infrastructure of the company.
- Performed numerous marketing and branding design requirements

### Alta Vision Solar Ltd · Colombo, Sri Lanka Software Engineer

Jun 2015 - Jan 2018

- Responsible for all marketing material for the company and for all client projects received.
- Designed, developed, tested and deployed multiple Laravel projects and WordPress websites.
- In charge of the Graphic design projects.

### Sri Lanka Telecom · Trincomalee, Sri Lanka

Oct 2016 - Dec 2016

### **Telecom Engineering Intern**

- Mentored by the industries finest Telecom Engineers including the regional manager himself.
- Learned all the soft skills necessary for any trade.

# Sri Lanka Telecom · Trincomalee, Sri Lanka Telecom Engineering Intern

Oct 2015 - Jan 2016

• Provided with basic training required for a career in Telecommunications Engineering.

### **EDUCATION**

### University of Sunderland · Sunderland, United Kingdom

Bachelor of Science (Honors) Computer Systems Engineering

### International College of Business and Technology · Colombo, Sri Lanka

Higher National Diploma in Software Engineering

### Institution of Engineers Sri Lanka College of Engineering · Colombo, Sri Lanka

Graduate Diploma in Electronics & Telecommunications Engineering